which means it was at the top of the food chain
Without any natural enemies.
As a top consumer, Megalodon had an important role
in keeping the ecosystem of the sea in balance.
It held the populations of other marine animals
As whales and large fish under control.
This helped to maintain a healthy diversity
and prevented a certain species from becoming overdominating,
which can lead to imbalance in the ecosystem.
Megalodon
body length varies slightly depending on the source
And some researchers estimate a length of up to 24 meters.
For the largest individuals.
If we compare megalodone with today's sea animals like that
Can you see a little clearer how big megalodone was.
A full -grown white shark can reach a length of up to six meters.
A killer whale can reach a length of
up to nine meters and the elections may easily reach a
Length of between 16 to 18 meters.
A LED bus has a length of about 18.75
meters and as I mentioned earlier so could a megalodon
have a length of between 15 to 24 meters
This massive size and weight required a huge energy
A megalodone needed to eat approximately
1.1 tons of food every day
And that corresponds to about two grown cows.
But it wasn't cows that megalodone ate
Fossil evidence shows that megalodon chased whales
For example, caskets and greenlands,
But also other marine animals such as seals,
Sea turtles and dolphins.
Probably megalodone also had cannibalism tendencies,
So they could eat each other in the absence of other foods.
They are not uncommon among sharks.
As I mentioned earlier so means
To easily bite steel.
It is believed that Megalodon gave birth to live kids.
However, it is unclear if the species was ovovivipar
meaning the eggs remained inside
modern and hatched there or if it were “vivipar” there
The fertilized embryos were given continuous nutrition directly from the mother.
Like mammals.
Assessments based on teeth from young individuals
suggests that recently born megalodonians
may have been at least two meters long.
Megalodon Ann's in the seas almost all over the world.
Fossil finds of megalodone has been discovered
on each continent except Antarctica.
It thrived in warm coastal waters, but also had the ability to
dive deeply as it chased after its prey.
When talking about prehistoric animals as dinosaurs
so we often think about their skeleton
And how come we only found teeth from Megalodon?
Shouldn't there be skeletal parts?
The truth is that
Hajar's skeleton is not made of legs.
Their skeleton is made of cartilage.
Same soft and flexible materials available
In your ears and your nose tip.
This applies to all sharks from the white shark to the whale shark.
The cartilage is softer
than legs and does not harden as easily over time.
So when a shark dies, the cartilage breaks down faster than legs
And that's why we don't find old shark skeletons
As we do with, for example, dinosaurs.
But some of the shark not made
of cartilage is their teeth.
The teeth are hard and can remain in the ground
in millions of years and it is through
these massive teeth that we have been able to draw conclusions about the size of megalodon
Diet and distribution.
The final question
Well, why is no megalodone left anymore?
There are several
Reasons why it is believed that Megalodon died out.
The earth became cooler during the time the time when megalodon was alive
The ice was expanded at the poles and the sea level fell,
Which limited Megalodon's habitat and access to food.
And even if megalodone managed colder water
made the big changes in the sea that
difficult for it to survive.
Whales and other large prey animals that were important to megalodone
moved to other parts of the seas as it got colder,
which forced megalodone to compete
With, among other things, the white shark about the smaller exchanges.
The white shark was faster and more adaptable when hunting for these changes
And besides, it was so that even if Megalodon
managed to catch these minor changes
so required its huge size such a large amount
feed that they could not maintain their energy needs.
Megalodons